Guide to the Marvin B. Kunze papers, 1960-1988 and undated RL.11559
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marvin B. Kunze papers
1960-1988 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kunze, Marvin
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11559
3.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive who worked for Benton & Bowles and Young & Rubicam agencies in New York, Germany and Sweden. Collection includes print advertisements, storyboards, sketches, scripts for radio and television commercials, photographs, slides, other printed materials, audio tape reels and television commercials on videotape and 16mm and 35mm films. Companies represented include Benton & Bowles, Bushmill's, Chesebrough-Pond's, Drackett (Nutrament), Eastern Airlines, General Foods (Sanka, Yuban), Goodyear, Gulf Oil, Kemp Seafood, Piels beer, Procter & Gamble, Texaco, Trygg Hansa, United Fruit (Chiquita) and Young & Rubicam. Materials are in English, German and Swedish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Professional files; Audiovisual materials.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive who worked for Benton & Bowles and Young & Rubicam agencies in New York, Germany and Sweden. Born 1929. Graduate Pratt Institute (Advertising Design) 1950. Started career at Benton & Bowles as an apprentice Art Director(New York) 1950. Military service 1951-1953; Young & Rubicam: Television Art Director, Art Supervisor (New York)1953-1964; Associate Creative Director (New York) 1964-1968; Vice President/Creative Director (Frenkfurt, Germany) 1968-1970; Vice President/Creative Director (Stockholm, Sweden) 1970-1973; Associate Creative Director/Director of Television and Radio Production (Frankfurt) 1973-1975; Associate Creative Director (New York) 1975-1978. Benton & Bowles: Creative Supervisor (New York) 1978-1986. Freelance: Blakemore & Killough, and Baumwoll & Tannen 1986-1987.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Marvin B. Kunze papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Adrienne Cohen papers
Arthur Einstein papers
D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles Archives
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements
Victor G. Bloede papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes print advertisements, storyboards, sketches, scripts for radio and television commercials, photographs, slides, other printed materials, audio tape reels and television commercials on videotape and 16mm and 35mm films. Companies represented include Benton & Bowles, Bushmill's, Chesebrough-Pond's, Drackett (Nutrament), Eastern Airlines, General Foods (Sanka, Yuban), Goodyear, Gulf Oil, Kemp Seafood, Piels beer, Procter & Gamble, Texaco, Trygg Hansa, United Fruit (Chiquita) and Young & Rubicam. Materials are in English, German and Swedish. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising agencies -- Germany; Advertising agencies -- Scandinavia; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Young & Rubicam; Benton & Bowles; Gulf Oil Corporation; Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company; Chesebrough-Pond's.; Procter & Gamble Company; Gulf Oil Corporation; United Fruit Company; Eastern Air Lines, Inc.; Drackett Company; General Foods Corporation
- Professional Files, 1960-1988 and undated; 1
  - Baumwoll & Tannen--Kemp Seafood, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Benton & Bowles--Photographs, slides from Bushmill trip, circa 1984 (Box 1)
  - Benton & Bowles--Print advertisements, 1980-1985; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes Bolla, Bushmills Whiskey; Texaco
  - Benton & Bowles--Storyboards, 1975-1983; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes Eckrich Meats, Procter & Gamble (Crest, Full Course, Omni, Task), Yuban
  - Biographical information, 1972-1980s (Box 1)
  - Blakemore & Killough--Print advertisements, 1987; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Includes Advertising Age, Morgan Stanley
  - D'Arcy Masius Benton & Bowles--Benefit Highlights, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Martell print advertisements, undated (Box 1)
  - Printed material--Art Directors Annual fur werbung und zeitschriften (German and English), 1966 (Box 3)
  - Printed material--Young & Rubicam office profile, circa 1971 (Box 3)
  - U.S. commercials worked on, undated (Box 1)
  - Young & Rubicam--Group photograph, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Young & Rubicam--Group photograph, circa 1961; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Young & Rubicam--Print advertisements (Nutrament), 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Young & Rubicam--Print advertisements--Germany (United Fruit/Chiquita; USA Tourism; in German), circa 1970-1976 (Box 2)
  - Young & Rubicam--Print advertisements--Germany (Nutrament, Pond's, United Fruit/Chiquita; USA Tourism; in English and German, 1970-1977; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Young & Rubicam--Print advertisements--Sweden (Trygg Hansa Insurance; in Swedish), circa 1971 (Box 4)
  - Young & Rubicam--Storyboards (Piels, Eastern Airlines), 1960-1966 (Box 2)
  - Young & Rubicam--Storyboards (Sanka), 1961 (Box 2)
  - Young & Rubicam--Transcripts of television commercials, undated (Box 2)
    Includes work from Germany (Pond's, United Fruit/Chiquita, Ludwig Eches/Chantre, Oil of Olay) and Sweden (Trygg Hansa Insurance, Gevalia, Bregott, Opel Rallye, Mum 21)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1976-1983 and undated; 2
  - Behold "Presenter" :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-001)
  - Benton & Bowles--Eckrich "Balloons", undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-002)
  - Benton & Bowles--Eckrich "He Likes It", undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-003)
  - Benton & Bowles--Texaco Fire Engine, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-004)
  - Benton & Bowles--Texaco "Gasohol" :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-005)
  - Benton & Bowles--Texaco "Hot Rocks" :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-006)
  - Benton & Bowles--Texaco "Hot Rocks" :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-007)
  - Benton & Bowles--Texaco "Montebello" Hop-79 :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-008)
  - Benton & Bowles--Texaco "Montebello" H-II-79 :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-009)
  - Benton & Bowles--Texaco "Montebello" H-II-79 :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-010)
  - Compilation, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-011)
    Goodyear "Glass Test"; Renuzit "Norman"; Behold "Crayon"; Windex "I Can See Clearly" "Submarine"; Gulf "Drain Change" "Hitchhiker"; Dash "Closet"; Lipton "Football" "Military"
  - DJM1093--Klosterberg-Eddy/Sinular; Moran & Mint, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-012)
  - Roy Anderson "Fazer", undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-013)
  - Swedish compilation, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-014)
    Mum 21; Gevalia Coffee; Trygghansa; Eckrich animated spots
  - Swedish compilation, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-015)
    Opel Rallye; Bregott; Trygghansa Beach
  - Young & Rubicam--Crest "Catapult", undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-016)
  - Young & Rubicam--Crest "Underground", undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-017)
  - Young & Rubicam--Dash "Closet", undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-018)
  - Young & Rubicam--Dash "Gang Disco", undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-019)
  - Young & Rubicam--Gulf compilation, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-020)
    Enough; Parking Lot; Snorkel; Check Research
  - Young & Rubicam--Gulf "Drain and Change" :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-021)
  - Young & Rubicam--Gulf "Hitchiker" :60, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-022)
  - Young & Rubicam--Gulf "Hitchiker" :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-023)
  - Young & Rubicam--Gulf "Hitchiker" :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-024)
  - Young & Rubicam--Gulf "Old Couple" :30, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F16-025)
  - German compilation, undated (Box AV1, Film-reel RL11559-F35-001)
    Pond's "Second Face"; Chiquita "Astronaut"; Oil of Olay "Verushka"; Chantre "Customs"
  - Kelso Herston Entreprises show reel, undated (Box AV1, Audio-reel RL11559-RR-001)
  - Benton & Bowles--Bolla Brut "Party" :30 Umatic, 1983 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11559-UMATIC-001)
  - Marvin Kunze sample reel (Copy) Umatic, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11559-UMATIC-002)
  - Marvin Kunze sample reel (Master) Umatic, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11559-UMATIC-003)
    Includes: Goodyear, Windex, Gulf, Lipton, Bolla, Crest, Eckrich, Yuban, German Pond's, Astronaut, Verushka, Shantray, Opel Rallye, Nipples, Boat, Margarine, Slick Tire, Old Lady
  - Marvin Kunze short reel Umatic, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11559-UMATIC-004)
  - Young & Rubicam--Gulf Oil "Drain and Change" Umatic, 1976 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11559-UMATIC-005)